Rishav Rana

Senior Business Analyst with overall 5 Years of Experience

Contact

Cell: (519) 991-7503

officialrishav1994@gmail.com LinkedIn Portfolio

Key Skills

- SQL Programming
- Data Modeling and Mining
- Data Science
- Business Intelligence (BI)
- Machine /Deep Learning
- Python
- UNIX
- R (Programming Language)
- Power BI and Tableau
- Power Automation
- Snowflake
- Report Generation
- Agile
- Communication and writing

IDE

- Microsoft SQL Server Studio
- Jupyter
- GitHub
- VS Studio
- Spyder
- Anaconda
- R Studio
- Service Now
- JIRA
- Snowflake IDE

Business Intelligence Analyst proficient at responding to shifting business needs and priorities in a systematic and effective way. Well versed in implementation of operational assessments and conducting functional requirements analysis for businesses of all sizes. Quantitative expert with exceptional speed in analysis of quarterly and annual reports and providing comprehensive syntheses.

Education

2022-2023

Post-Graduation in Data Analytics • St. Clair College • Windsor, Ontario

2013-2017

Bachelor's in Engineering • Chandigarh Engineering College • India

Experience

BI Analyst

Capgemini Ltd. | Pune, India

02/2018 - 12/2021

- Synthesized current business intelligence data to produce reports and polished presentations, highlighting findings and recommending changes.
- Drafted quarterly and yearly reports on company financial metrics to assess successes and account for deficiencies.
- Reviewed files, records, and other documents to obtain business information and key data informing responses to development requests.
- Played a key role in the integration of Snowflake data lakes, optimizing data storage and accessibility.
- Evaluated consistency and importance of different business intelligence data against needs to determine optimal courses of action.
- Utilized business intelligence, analytics, and data visualization tools such as Tableau to analyze and present data insights to stakeholders.
- Leveraged Python and Databricks for data manipulation and analysis, streamlining processes and improving efficiency.
- Developed and optimized SQL queries to extract and manipulate data from databases, ensuring data accuracy and integrity.

Student Researcher

07/2022 - 08/2023

St. Clair College | Windsor, Canada

- Conducted data collection and preprocessing for driver drowsiness detection.
- Assisted in implementing machine learning techniques for analyzing driver behavior data
- Contributed to creating data visualizations to depict patterns and trends in drowsiness-related data.
- Conducted research on machine learning algorithms and techniques relevant to driver drowsiness detection.
- Supported documentation and reporting efforts for research findings and project progress.

Achievement and Awards

- Led Drowsiness Detection capstone project team and helped secure top position with exceptional leadership and collaboration.
- Achieved several Star of the Month awards for performing exceptionally well.
- Promoted with multiple promotions for my outstanding performance and organizational impact ahead of schedule by 12 months.